[mysterious music]
It makes no sense that our
monastery is way out here.
How is this even possible?
Because this isn't
our monastery.
Whoa.
From the outside,
it looks exactly the same,
but in here, pretty different.
For real. As if someone liked
your crumbly old monastery
so much they were like,
"I'll have my own, please."
I mean, your nice monastery.
[Cole] If Mysterium
is a land of magic,
could this be an
illusion or something?
Scans confirm
its solid existence.
Bonzle, the Sorceress
created you here?
I mean, in roughly this spot,
but there was
no building here then.
The Sorceress is
probably long gone,
if she'd even remember
or recognize me.
After the Merge,
I awoke inside a strange second
monastery under Imperium,
something I have not yet
been able to explain.
And now, we have
a third monastery.
Hmm, puzzling.
Both of you, come! Look!
[Bonzle] A crack
in the wall? So?
Long time ago,
back in our monastery,
my teammate Jay
and I got into a fight
because he was totally annoying
and I was completely blameless.
[electricity surges]
-[gadget whooshes]
-[wall cracks]
Anyway, during the fight,
we broke the wall,
making a crack in the shape
of a bowl of noodles.
[Zane] Cole and Jay thought
it looked so delicious,
they got hungry,
stopped the fight,
and went to Chen's
Noodle House together.
That's the weirdest way to end
a fight I've ever heard.
The point is that's
the exact crack we made.
But how could this monastery
have the same cracks in
the walls as our monastery?
I don't know, but
it's making me hungry.
I wish that bonehead
Jay was around.
Who knows where he
ended up after the Merge?
[Sprite whirring]
You saw that too, right?
We have witnessed similar
unexplained phenomena
at our monastery.
The post-Merge world
has so many mysteries.
If only someone would arrive
and tell us everything
we need to know.
Hi! Oh, you have no idea
how glad I am
to set eyes on you.
Sprite told me you
finally got here.
I am Gandalaria, the High
Sorceress of Mysterium,
and I have awaited your coming
for quite some time.
This will change everything!
♪ Lost in the unknown ♪
♪ So much to see ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ We fight ♪
♪ Be a ninja for what's right ♪
[explosion booms]
[intense music]
-[Arin grunting]
-[columns crumbling]
[Arin] Ah!
[Arin pants, groans]
All right! Yeah!
Sorry, didn't mean
to sneak up on you, Arin.
I'm just trying to practice
Spinjitzu on my own.
And you're doing great!
Don't make fun of me, Sora.
You know I got demoted
down to First Fang.
I'm not making fun of you.
You plowed right through
those first two pillars.
I was trying to go
through all three
with a proper Spinjitzu
tornado, for once.
Your Spinjitzu's been
great since I met you.
I mean, you can give Spinjitzu
to inanimate objects.
No one can do that.
I can barely do that.
Stop being so hard on yourself.
The Blood Moon is coming!
The whole world is at stake!
We're the only ones
who can stop it,
and I need to be getting
better at being a Ninja,
but I'm not.
[calm music]
I came here alone because I
do not wish to be disturbed.
Yeah, me too.
Sometimes all those other
Ninja can get on my nerves.
I mean, Kai's friends
are all good people,
but I'm not used to being
around humans all the time.
I was raised by dragons.
Did you know that?
You may have mentioned it
once or 12 times.
Yeah, so I fit in better
with you and Rontu
than the Ninja, really.
Mm-hmm.
My family used to
tell me stories.
I'm sure they were made up,
but they were very good.
Some were about the two
greatest dragon warriors
-that ever lived.
-Is that so?
Yeah, these warriors were epic.
Legendary.
They went to all the realms,
protecting everyone who
couldn't protect themselves
whether they were
dragons or not.
And the older dragon
was the bravest warrior
anyone had ever seen.
Hmm, was he, now?
Yep. We even named the largest
strongest mountain in our land
after him: Mount Egalt.
But those stories were
probably all just fairy tales.
There was a time when those
stories could have been true,
but that is long past.
Time runs out for everyone,
even once-great warriors.
I made you a stew from
Janus Melons and Xoa Thorns.
It helps ease the pain
of the Wasting Sickness.
[grunts] What are you
talking about?
I lost some of my
own dragon family to it.
I know it's a disease
older dragons can get.
And what makes you believe
I suffer from this ailment?
The black edges
of your lost scales.
That only happens when the
sickness is getting really bad.
This isn't a cure, but it
makes the pain less painful.
I don't need any stew.
I just need to be left alone.
Irritability is
one of the symptoms
of Wasting Sickness too,
but that could also just
be your personality.
Ha!
So, they named
a mountain after me, huh?
Now, pay attention.
This is very important.
I'll need 20 striped ones,
five red betties,
and two extra-slimy.
I am sorry.
We do not understand.
What?
What's not to understand?
Oh, and do you have
any with wings?
I could really use
some with wings.
Some whats with wings?
Slugs, of course.
Aren't you
the traveling slug merchants
I've been waiting for?
Slug merchants?
But you said our arrival
would change everything.
Uh, yeah!
I've been very low on
rare magic ingredients
for, like, weeks now, and
a really good set of slugs
would change all that.
Slugs are pretty cool,
actually.
Perhaps, yet we
have none to sell.
Ah, bummer. Well, what
am I going to do now?
Would you all mind if
I turn you into slugs?
We would mind that
very, very much.
Are you sure?
Because you'd make
really groovy slugs,
I can tell
just by looking at...
[gasps] It's you!
My dearest!
You've come home!
You... You recognize me?
Even in my boney physical form?
Oh, I would know
your true essence anywhere.
I was so afraid you wouldn't
accept me for who I am now.
Are you kidding?
I put my heart, my soul
into every spell I weave.
And even though spells
usually fade away after use,
I always hoped you
would be different--
the most complex spell
I've ever woven,
and the first of my creations
to ever come back to me!
Oh!
[Lloyd sips]
[sighs]
[Rontu sips, gulps]
So you're afraid these
visions are holding you back
from progressing with
your Rising Dragon training?
I'm just a bundle of nerves,
stumbling around in a daze.
I'm even afraid to rest because
more visions might come.
Why would that be a bad thing?
Because they're terrifying!
I see evil things.
My friends in danger,
it's awful.
I'm sure it is,
but these visions are also
important warnings, right?
[sighs]
They are, but they're
also tearing me apart.
Master Wu taught that when
there is no calm outside of you,
you must find the calm inside,
but I have no calm
inside of me anymore.
You held the power
of a Source Dragon,
something no mortal
was ever meant to do.
These possible futures
are after-effects.
Possible futures?
Source Dragons experience
time differently
than the rest of us.
They can see what came before
and the things that
might come to be.
These visions you're having
are like a fragment of that.
But how can I stop them?
You can't.
You can never force
the motion of the universe
to bend to your will,
you can only find your
place within its current.
But with careful meditation,
it's possible you can find
harmony with these visions
so you no longer have
to live in fear of them.
No. I need to stop them.
Because when they come on,
I can't-- [shouts]
[eerie music]
But that will kill him!
[weapons clanging]
[explosion booms]
[yells]
The Blood Moon!
It's so close!
It's almost here!
Unless we stop him, Lord Ras
is going to sacrifice someone,
and Cole and Zane are doomed!
Then time is of the essence.
Return to training immediately.
If you cannot learn
Rising Dragon Technique,
all will be lost.
[calm music]
Ahem, uh, Sorceress?
Please, call me Gandalaria.
Of course.
Gadull-- Gandollar, uh...
Sorceress, we came because
we gotta protect Bonzle.
Scary Wolf Mask
people are after her
so their Lord Ras can use her
to unleash evil
on the Merged lands.
Okay, now I might've been
getting a little slow
on the uptake for the last
couple of hundred years,
but what's a Bonzle,
or a Lord Ras?
I'm Bonzle. That's the name
I chose when I became a person.
Well, that's a splendid name.
Lord Ras is a villain
we Ninja have faced before.
He is determined
to free the Forbidden Five.
The foes I created
Bonzle to banish?
-Exactly.
-Ah, pfft, then no problem.
They're gone, exiled,
never able to return.
-You're certain?
-Of course.
First off, it'd take
a whole complicated ritual
that no one remembers how to
do,
and second, it could only
be done under a Blood Moon,
and those happen like
once a millennium.
It appears we have bad news.
The details of the ritual
were recovered by Lord Ras
from the Cloud Kingdom
archives.
And the Blood Moon
is coming soon.
Oh. Oh!
Yes, that does change things.
If this Ras times it right,
reversing
the power of the spell--
uh, Bonzle here--
I suppose he could
very well free the Five.
And from what we understand,
if they get loose, they
could conquer everything.
Conquer?
More like obliterate!
You musn't allow
them to be freed!
We hoped you would know a way
to keep Bonzle safely
out of Ras' hands
until the Blood Moon passes.
Before I moved
into this new place,
I used to wander the lands.
I keep most of
my materials in storage.
So you have nothing
to help us with?
Well, not here, but I
certainly do in my storehouse.
It's in a land
called the Wyldness.
It'll be quite
a journey on foot.
Good news. We've got
our fastest dragon
parked right outside.
Ooh, how delightful!
I haven't ridden
on dragonback for a century!
[gate thudding]
[Cole] Did the Wolf Masks
follow us here?
I do not believe
they would knock.
However, it would be wise
to discover who is outside
before we open that gate.
If it's a snail merchant,
ask about the ones with wings!
Unfortunately, it is not.
Attention!
My name is Agent Roderick
Allen, and this is my partner,
Agent Underwood.
By the all-encompassing
authority of The Administration,
we hereby demand
you open this door!
We're after the stolen
equipment known as Zane,
who illegally fled from us!
Cole, have I mentioned
that I was briefly kidnapped
by a society of bureaucrats
from the Land of Madness
who forced me to work
in their mail room,
where I introduced
efficiencies that raised
delivery accuracy by nearly 9%?
Are you serious?
Yes, nearly 9%.
I feel I could have
gotten it to ten,
but Lloyd and Arin rescued me
before I could finish.
Bureaucrats? Pfft!
Probably wouldn't even
make good slugs then.
-[intense music]
-[Kai's Spinjitzu whirring]
[Kai yelps]
[groans] Come on!
This is impossible!
It's too much!
Did I not tell you
it would be impossible?
Rising Dragon Technique is not
for those lacking in spirit.
Who are you saying
lacks spirit? Me?
You better not be
talking about me.
So quick to anger.
It is no surprise
you cannot find harmony
with the universe's motion.
What if we did
this drill together?
What?
You say Rising Dragon Technique
is about finding
harmony with everything,
which means harmony
with each other, right?
It does.
Then, let my brother
and I try this together.
That is unprecedented,
but I don't have
a problem with it.
Though it will most
likely end in failure.
What are you doing?
I can do this myself, Nya.
So far, you're doing
better than any of us,
but I know what's
holding you back.
-What?
-You. Stop thinking about you.
Start thinking
about Counter Shot.
The game we made up
in Dad's blacksmith shop?
[chuckles]
Wow, miss those days.
Just fun, not having to worry
about saving the world.
And who was your best
Counter Shot partner?
[Egalt] Begin!
[Spinjitzus whirring]
[epic music]
[epic music continues]
[Kai whooshes]
[horseshoes clang]
-[Spinjitzus whirring]
-[targets clang]
[epic music builds]
[horseshoes whooshing]
-[epic music continues]
-[pots breaking]
[boulders breaking]
[epic music continues]
[dragon roaring]
-[epic music building]
-[dragon whooshing]
[epic music climaxes
then fades out]
-[dragon roars]
-[explosion booms]
[gasps]
I did it! I did it!
Nya, thank you so much!
Ohh, you were so right!
[all cheering]
Kai is now officially
a Third Fang Ninja.
When you first arrived,
I was skeptical.
But I had become old and tired,
without inspiration,
and it was clear
I misjudged you.
You are worthy students
and have given this old dragon
the spark of hope
that Rising Dragon
Technique will be passed on.
What's wrong with the sky?
Oh, no.
[ominous music]
[dramatic music]
The Blood Moon is here.
Come on!
We have no time to waste.
Help the rest of us learn how
to do Rising Dragon Technique.
We cannot. I'm sorry.
We hoped we had more time,
but the Blood Moon
is also a bane for us.
May the Source Dragons
be on your side.
[dramatic music continues]
Excuse me. We have some rather
pressing matters to attend to.
Would it be easiest
for my allies here
if I just surrendered?
Technically, you can't
surrender, only people can.
You're a robotic Nindroid,
so you're classified
as equipment, not personnel.
Which means you'll
be decommissioned
in our incinerator.
But that will kill him!
Correction, it would kill
him, if he were a person.
But he's just equipment,
so no big deal.
But if I turn myself over,
my friends can go free?
Nope. Don't you
know Addendum 47-A?
Anyone assisting
a known fugitive
shall be punished under
the strictest guidelines.
Not much room for
misinterpretation there.
Whatever. Let's just get on
our dragon and go, everyone.
Nice try, but your dragon's
currently impounded.
[Jiro roars]
[Cole] Hey! Let Jiro go!
We can discuss it on the way
to the incinerator.
Breach this wall!
Halt!
Where is your 35-C91 form,
designating approved
intent to breach a wall
or barricade on foreign soil?
Did you just make that up?
No. My work in the mail room
afforded me
much access to handbooks.
My knowledge
of their regulations is vast.
[groans] Intent to breach
water. Intent to breach
walrus.
Ah, here it is!
Intent to breach walls.
Ugh, he's right.
We need forms!
[groans]
Okay, give us a minute.
We'll get right
on the paperwork.
Man, none of this stuff
is Administration-approved,
and you brought them
right to my door!
-[cat yowls]
-Not cool!
We passed through
the Land of Madness to get here.
I should have realized
they would be scanning for me.
This is all my fault.
No. We're in this together.
[Agent Underwood]
There's your 35-C91! Hmm!
This doesn't have
the mandatory 5-21z appendix.
Unacceptable.
[Agent Allen]
Ugh, he's right again!
Who's got a copy
of the appendix?
I know what to do! I'll weave
an intricate escape spell.
How long will that take?
Only two to three days.
That might be too long.
[Agent Allen] Appendix
attached, you scofflaw.
This is done correctly...
-Told you.
-...but not in triplicate.
-[Agent Allan screams]
-[gate thuds]
Bonzle, hide in the passages
under this place.
Sprite will guide you.
Thanks, Sprite.
But what are you gonna do?
I'm going to fire up
my crystal ball!
I'm not sure offering to read
their fortune is gonna help.
It's not that kind
of crystal ball.
-[ominous music]
-[gate crumbles]
There's your
triplicate right there!
[blasts blaring]
-[crystal ball surging]
-[Sorceress laughing]
-[intense music]
-[mech assembling]
[mechs clanging]
[blasts blaring
and connecting]
-[crystal ball surging]
-[Sorceress cackling]
[sighs] Everything's so dark
down here, Sprite.
Are you sure there'll
be a safe place to hide?
-[blast lands]
-[Agent Walker] Attention!
[mysterious music]
My name
is Agent Jay Walker!
By the all-encompassing
authority of the Administration,
I hereby demand your surrender!
[dramatic music]
[closing theme music playing]